Ales Loncar

Daytime maker of code, midnight baker / cook | Slovenian expat

München, Bayern DE

http://loncar.net

loncarales loncarales loncarales



With the strong technical background and two decades of experience spanning various client, server and cloud infrastructure technologies. I'm a Software Engineer first and foremost who is never shy to reach out for a terminal. I always leave code and processes in better shape than when I first encountered them (Boy Scout Rule). Proactive problem solver. A team player and passionate about working with talented teammates. I like to learn, experiment and utilise new technologies, concepts and procedures as appropriate to project requirements. I embrace DevOps culture, Cloud Native and I like to build software in a "You build it, you run it" manner.

These days I work with:

- Java, Spring Boot, Gradle
- Go (golang)
- Ansible, Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube
- Docker and container orchestration solutions (Kubernetes, RedHat OpenShift)
- Microservice Architectures
- Modernising legacy monoliths and infrastructures



WORK EXPERIENCE (6)

Senior Software Engineer at Catenate July 2018- Current

https://catenate.com/

java gradle spring boot jenkins docker kubernetes red hat openshift prometheus nexus sonarqube

Being a part of the self-organises agile squad (Team Cup O' Code) where continual learning and experimentation in our daily work enable us to achieve the organisation's goals. Acting as a Team Lead/Agile Coach/Developer. My task spawns from leading technical discussions and debate issues with the engineering team and also get my hands a little dirty cutting code. From writing User Stories based on business requirements, doing code reviews, daily standups, meetings with clients, weekly retrospectives, coordination and collaboration to inspiring the team and taking care of that there are no impediments in the project. We are actively managing our technical debt by ensuring that we invest at least 20% of all cycles for non-functional requirements such as maintainability, manageability, reliability, testability, deployability, and security.

- Team Lead of a small agile team
- Processes implementation and improvement (optimization)
- Perceived mentor: training other developers, pair programming
- Tech talks: Cloud Computing, Containers and Container orchestration, DevOps Myths and Misconceptions, Vagrant, OpenShift, ...

Software Engineer CAD/CAM at Etkon GmbH/Straumann Group February 2016- June 2018 http://www.straumann.com/ perl ansible gitlab gitlab ci docker kubernetes go (golang) mysql redis microservices

I am part of a Software Development Team in CAD/CAM department which is responsible for: * software solutions to automate CAD/CAM production processes * software solutions for mass processing data in 3D * database-driven production logistics processes * development of interfaces to various IT systems (web services and other protocols) and CNC machines for manufacturing * development of intranet applications to support the production workflow

- Develop new functionality and refactoring of existing functionality
- Processes implementation and improvement (optimization)
- Proactively learn and utilize new technologies, concepts, and procedures as appropriate to project requirements
- Code reviews
- Perceived mentor: training other developers, pair programming



Acting as game / software developer in the Travian 5 Games department. Mostly involved in development of tools for Travian 5 game and building communication layers between Travian 5 game and 3rd party tools. Supported team migration from Gitorious to Stash.

- Agile software development process: sprint planning, user story estimations, retrospectives and daily scrum meetings
- Daily usage of Atlassian tools for more efficient development process
- Develop new functionality and refactoring of existing functionality
- Proactively learn and utilize new technologies, concepts, and procedures as appropriate to project requirements
- Processes implementation and improvement (optimisation)
- Code reviews

Perceived mentor: training other developers, pair programming

Senior Developer at Central European Media Enterprises January 2011- February 2013

http://www.cetv-net.com

php zend framework javascript jquery android widevine mysql doctrine

Developer on numerous projects: Voyo, Common Content Platform, Smart TV development. Working closely with central and local teams developing, integrating and coordinating deployment of new features

- Voyo Video On Demand Platform (TVOD, AVOD, SVOD, EST, PPV, LIVE Streaming)
- CME Common Content Platform (Zend Framework)
- API's for connected Mobile, Smart TV and STB devices (JSON-RPC, REST)
- Android development (Phone, Tablet, STB)
- Modules for Wowza Media Server
- Video trans-coding workflow implementing Google Widevine DRM

Web / Mobile Developer at Kitio d.o.o. December 2008- December 2010

http://www.kitio.com

php zend framework javascript jquery extjs xhtml css mysql

Developer on multiple web & mobile projects including creating socile mobile portal called iSPACE.

- Web & mobile application development (using PHP with Zend Framework, jQuery & Ajax UI, XHTML, CSS
- SMS publisher for iSpace portal
- Real-time SMS chat web interface

Web Developer at AV studio d.o.o. September 2000- November 2008

http://www.av-studio.si

asp mssql javascript xhtml css

Developer on multiple web projects build on AV SiteKit (Content management system).

- Programming in ASP with Microsoft solutions
- Network and systems administration
- development and integration of AV SiteKit

VOLUNTEER

Developer/Administrator/Editor at RockOnNet

September 2002 - September 2013

http://www.rockonnet.com

php javascript mysql photography apache linux

RockOnNet is an online magazine for music enthusiasts. I've developed it in 2002 and it soon became an online think tank for young photographers and writers who wanted to share their thoughts about music. It is still alive and kicking to this day.

Proactively working as developer, administrator and editor of RockOnNet web magazine.

EDUCATION (2)

Dropout at Faculty of Computer and Information Science

1994 - 1999

High school diploma at Gimnazija Murska Sobota

1990 - 1994

AWARDS

Honorable Mention @ Izzivamo Ideje at Si.mobil

4 - 10 place with Android application: KjeSeRoka. The results of the event 'Izzivamo Ideje' Results

LANGUAGES

Slovenian English German
Native speaker Fluent Fluent

INTERESTS

reading

photography

cooking/baking

epic fantasy r. a. salvatore drizzt do'urden

My obsessesion with photography gave a birth of an online magazine RockOnNet

I am a fan of epic fantasy novels especially from R. A. Salvatore.